<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry type="method" name="ajaxError" return="jQuery">
  <title>.ajaxError()</title>
  <signature>
    <added>1.0</added>
    <argument name="handler(event, jqXHR, ajaxSettings, thrownError)" type="Function">
      <desc>The function to be invoked.</desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <desc>Register a handler to be called when Ajax requests complete with an error. This is an <a href="/Ajax_Events/">Ajax Event</a>.</desc>
  <longdesc>
    <p>Whenever an Ajax request completes with an error, jQuery triggers the <code>ajaxError</code> event. Any and all handlers that have been registered with the <code>.ajaxError()</code> method are executed at this time. <strong>Note:</strong> <em>This handler is not called for cross-domain script and cross-domain JSONP requests.</em></p>
    <p>To observe this method in action, set up a basic Ajax load request.</p>
    <pre><code>
&lt;button class="trigger"&gt;Trigger&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;div class="result"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="log"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    </code></pre>
    <p>Attach the event handler to the document:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( document ).ajaxError(function() {
  $( "div.log" ).text( "Triggered ajaxError handler." );
});
    </code></pre>
    <p>Now, make an Ajax request using any jQuery method:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "button.trigger" ).on( "click", function() {
  $( "div.result" ).load( "ajax/missing.html" );
});
    </code></pre>
    <p>When the user clicks the button and the Ajax request fails, because the requested file is missing, the log message is displayed.</p>
    <p><strong>As of jQuery 1.8, the <code>.ajaxError()</code> method should only be attached to <code>document</code>.</strong></p>
    <p>All <code>ajaxError</code> handlers are invoked, regardless of what Ajax request was completed. To differentiate between the requests, use the parameters passed to the handler. Each time an <code>ajaxError</code> handler is executed, it is passed the event object, the <code>jqXHR</code> object (prior to jQuery 1.5, the <code><abbr title="XMLHttpRequest">XHR</abbr></code> object), and the settings object that was used in the creation of the request. When an HTTP error occurs, the fourth argument (<code>thrownError</code>) receives the textual portion of the HTTP status, such as "Not Found" or "Internal Server Error." For example, to restrict the error callback to only handling events dealing with a particular URL:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( document ).ajaxError(function( event, jqxhr, settings, exception ) {
  if ( settings.url == "ajax/missing.html" ) {
    $( "div.log" ).text( "Triggered ajaxError handler." );
  }
});</code></pre>
  </longdesc>
  <note id="ajax-global-false" type="additional" data-title=".ajaxError()"/>
  <example>
    <desc>Show a message when an Ajax request fails.</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( document ).ajaxError(function( event, request, settings ) {
  $( "#msg" ).append( "<li>Error requesting page " + settings.url + "</li>" );
});
]]></code>
  </example>
  <category slug="ajax/global-ajax-event-handlers"/>
  <category slug="version/1.0"/>
</entry>
