<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry type="method" name="ajaxSuccess" return="jQuery">
  <title>.ajaxSuccess()</title>
  <signature>
    <added>1.0</added>
    <argument name="handler(event, XMLHttpRequest, ajaxOptions)" type="Function">
      <desc>The function to be invoked.</desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <desc>Attach a function to be executed whenever an Ajax request completes successfully. This is an <a href="/Ajax_Events/">Ajax Event</a>.</desc>
  <longdesc>
    <p>Whenever an Ajax request completes successfully, jQuery triggers the <code>ajaxSuccess</code> event. Any and all handlers that have been registered with the <code>.ajaxSuccess()</code> method are executed at this time.</p>
    <p>To observe this method in action, set up a basic Ajax load request:</p>
    <pre><code>
&lt;div class="trigger"&gt;Trigger&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="result"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="log"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    </code></pre>
    <p>Attach the event handler to any element:</p>
    <pre><code>
$(document).ajaxSuccess(function() {
  $( ".log" ).text( "Triggered ajaxSuccess handler." );
});
    </code></pre>
    <p>Now, make an Ajax request using any jQuery method:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( ".trigger" ).on( "click", function() {
  $( ".result" ).load( "ajax/test.html" );
});
    </code></pre>
    <p>When the user clicks the element with class <code>trigger</code> and the Ajax request completes successfully, the log message is displayed.</p>
    <p><strong>As of jQuery 1.8, the <code>.ajaxSuccess()</code> method should only be attached to <code>document</code>.</strong></p>
    <p>All <code>ajaxSuccess</code> handlers are invoked, regardless of what Ajax request was completed. If you must differentiate between the requests, you can use the parameters passed to the handler. Each time an <code>ajaxSuccess</code> handler is executed, it is passed the event object, the <code>XMLHttpRequest</code> object, and the settings object that was used in the creation of the request. For example, you can restrict the callback to only handling events dealing with a particular URL:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( document ).ajaxSuccess(function( event, xhr, settings ) {
  if ( settings.url == "ajax/test.html" ) {
    $( ".log" ).text( "Triggered ajaxSuccess handler. The ajax response was: " +
      xhr.responseText );
  }
});
    </code></pre>
    <p><strong>Note:</strong> You can get the returned ajax contents by looking at <code>xhr.responseXML</code> or <code>xhr.responseText</code> for xml and html respectively.</p>
  </longdesc>
  <note id="ajax-global-false" type="additional" data-title=".ajaxSuccess()"/>
  <example>
    <desc>Show a message when an Ajax request completes successfully.</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( document ).ajaxSuccess(function( event, request, settings ) {
  $( "#msg" ).append( "<li>Successful Request!</li>" );
});
]]></code>
  </example>
  <category slug="ajax/global-ajax-event-handlers"/>
  <category slug="version/1.0"/>
</entry>
