<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry type="method" name="ajaxSend" return="jQuery">
  <title>.ajaxSend()</title>
  <signature>
    <added>1.0</added>
    <argument name="handler(event, jqXHR, ajaxOptions)" type="Function">
      <desc>The function to be invoked.</desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <desc>Attach a function to be executed before an Ajax request is sent. This is an <a href="/Ajax_Events/">Ajax Event</a>.</desc>
  <longdesc>
    <p>Whenever an Ajax request is about to be sent, jQuery triggers the <code>ajaxSend</code> event. Any and all handlers that have been registered with the <code>.ajaxSend()</code> method are executed at this time.</p>
    <p>To observe this method in action, set up a basic Ajax load request:</p>
    <pre><code>
&lt;div class="trigger"&gt;Trigger&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="result"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="log"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    </code></pre>
    <p>Attach the event handler to the document:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( document ).ajaxSend(function() {
  $( ".log" ).text( "Triggered ajaxSend handler." );
});
    </code></pre>
    <p>Now, make an Ajax request using any jQuery method:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( ".trigger" ).click(function() {
  $( ".result" ).load( "ajax/test.html" );
});
    </code></pre>
    <p>When the user clicks the element with class <code>trigger</code> and the Ajax request is about to begin, the log message is displayed.</p>
    <p><strong>As of jQuery 1.8, the <code>.ajaxSend()</code> method should only be attached to <code>document</code>.</strong></p>
    <p>All <code>ajaxSend</code> handlers are invoked, regardless of what Ajax request is to be sent. If you must differentiate between the requests, use the parameters passed to the handler. Each time an <code>ajaxSend</code> handler is executed, it is passed the event object, the <code>jqXHR</code> object (in version 1.4, <code>XMLHttpRequest</code>object), and the <a href="/jQuery.ajax/">settings object</a> that was used in the creation of the Ajax request. For example, you can restrict the callback to only handling events dealing with a particular URL:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( document ).ajaxSend(function( event, jqxhr, settings ) {
  if ( settings.url == "ajax/test.html" ) {
    $( ".log" ).text( "Triggered ajaxSend handler." );
  }
});
    </code></pre>
  </longdesc>
  <note id="ajax-global-false" type="additional" data-title=".ajaxSend()"/>
  <example>
    <desc>Show a message before an Ajax request is sent.</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( document ).ajaxSend(function( event, request, settings ) {
  $( "#msg" ).append( "<li>Starting request at " + settings.url + "</li>" );
});
]]></code>
  </example>
  <category slug="ajax/global-ajax-event-handlers"/>
  <category slug="version/1.0"/>
</entry>
