<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry type="method" name="appendTo" return="jQuery">
  <title>.appendTo()</title>
  <signature>
    <added>1.0</added>
    <argument name="target">
      <desc>A selector, element, HTML string, array of elements, or jQuery object; the matched set of elements will be inserted at the end of the element(s) specified by this parameter.</desc>
      <type name="Selector"/>
      <type name="htmlString"/>
      <type name="Element"/>
      <type name="Array"/>
      <type name="jQuery"/>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <desc>Insert every element in the set of matched elements to the end of the target.</desc>
  <longdesc>
    <p>The <code><a href="/append/">.append()</a></code> and <code>.appendTo()</code> methods perform the same task. The major difference is in the syntax-specifically, in the placement of the content and target. With <code>.append()</code>, the selector expression preceding the method is the container into which the content is inserted. With <code>.appendTo()</code>, on the other hand, the content precedes the method, either as a selector expression or as markup created on the fly, and it is inserted into the target container.</p>
    <p>Consider the following HTML:</p>
    <pre><code>
&lt;h2&gt;Greetings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="container"&gt;
  &lt;div class="inner"&gt;Hello&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class="inner"&gt;Goodbye&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    </code></pre>
    <p>We can create content and insert it into several elements at once:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "&lt;p&gt;Test&lt;/p&gt;" ).appendTo( ".inner" );
    </code></pre>
    <p>Each inner <code>&lt;div&gt;</code> element gets this new content:</p>
    <pre><code>
&lt;h2&gt;Greetings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="container"&gt;
  &lt;div class="inner"&gt;
    Hello
    &lt;p&gt;Test&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class="inner"&gt;
    Goodbye
    &lt;p&gt;Test&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    </code></pre>
    <p>We can also select an element on the page and insert it into another:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "h2" ).appendTo( $( ".container" ) );
    </code></pre>
    <p>If an element selected this way is inserted into a single location elsewhere in the DOM, it will be moved into the target (not cloned) and a new set consisting of the inserted element is returned:</p>
    <pre><code>
&lt;div class="container"&gt;
  &lt;div class="inner"&gt;Hello&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class="inner"&gt;Goodbye&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Greetings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    </code></pre>
    <p>If there is more than one target element, however, cloned copies of the inserted element will be created for each target except the last, and that new set (the original element plus clones) is returned.</p>
	<p><strong>Before jQuery 1.9,</strong> the append-to-single-element case did not create a new set, but instead returned the original set which made it difficult to use the <code>.end()</code> method reliably when being used with an unknown number of elements.</p>
  </longdesc>
  <note id="html-code-execution" type="additional"/>
  <example>
    <desc>Append all spans to the element with the ID "foo" (Check append() documentation for more examples)</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( "span" ).appendTo( "#foo" );
]]></code>
    <css><![CDATA[
  #foo {
    background: yellow;
  }
]]></css>
    <html><![CDATA[
<span>I have nothing more to say... </span>

<div id="foo">FOO! </div>
]]></html>
  </example>
  <category slug="manipulation/dom-insertion-inside"/>
  <category slug="version/1.0"/>
</entry>
