<entry type='method' name="click" return="jQuery">
  <desc>Bind an event handler to the "click" JavaScript event, or trigger that event on an element.</desc>
  <signature>
    <added>1.0</added>
    <argument name="handler(eventObject)" type="Function">
      <desc>A function to execute each time the event is triggered.</desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <signature>
    <added>1.4.3</added>
    <argument name="eventData" type="Object" optional="true">
      <desc>A map of data that will be passed to the event handler.</desc>
    </argument>
    <argument name="handler(eventObject)" type="Function">
      <desc>A function to execute each time the event is triggered.</desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <signature>
    <added>1.0</added>
  </signature>

<longdesc>
<p>In the first two variations, this method is a shortcut for <code>.bind("click", handler)</code>, as well as for <code>.on("click", handler)</code> as of jQuery 1.7. In the third variation, when <code>.click()</code> is called without arguments, it is a shortcut for <code>.trigger("click")</code>. </p>
<p>The <code>click</code> event is sent to an element when the mouse pointer is over the element, and the mouse button is pressed and released. Any HTML element can receive this event.</p>
<pre>For example, consider the HTML:
&lt;div id="target"&gt;
  Click here
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="other"&gt;
  Trigger the handler
&lt;/div&gt;</pre>

<p class="image"><img src="/images/0042_05_03.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>The event handler can be bound to any <code>&lt;div&gt;</code>:</p>
<pre>$("#target").click(function() {
  alert("Handler for .click() called.");
});</pre>
<p>Now if we click on this element, the alert is displayed:</p>
<p><span class="output">Handler for .click() called.</span></p>
<p>We can also trigger the event when a different element is clicked:</p>
<pre>$("#other").click(function() {
  $("#target").click();
});</pre>
<p>After this code executes, clicks on <span class="output">Trigger the handler</span> will also alert the message.</p>
<p>The <code>click</code> event is only triggered after this exact series of events:</p>
<ul>
  <li>The mouse button is depressed while the pointer is inside the element.</li>
  <li>The mouse button is released while the pointer is inside the element.</li>
</ul>
<p>This is usually the desired sequence before taking an action. If this is not required, the <code>mousedown</code> or <code>mouseup</code> event may be more suitable.</p>
</longdesc>
                <example>
                    <desc>Hide paragraphs on a page when they are clicked:</desc>
                    <code><![CDATA[
    $("p").click(function () {
      $(this).slideUp();
    });
]]></code>
                    <css><![CDATA[
  p { color:red; margin:5px; cursor:pointer; }
  p:hover { background:yellow; }
  ]]></css>
                    <html><![CDATA[<p>First Paragraph</p>

  <p>Second Paragraph</p>
  <p>Yet one more Paragraph</p>]]></html>
                </example>
                <example>
                    <desc>Trigger the click event on all of the paragraphs on the page:</desc>
                    <code><![CDATA[$("p").click();]]></code>
                </example>

</entry>