<entry name="deferred.then" type="method" return="Deferred">
  <title>deferred.then()</title>
  <signature>
    <added>1.5</added>
    <argument name="doneCallbacks" type="Function">
      <desc>
        A function, or array of functions, called when the Deferred is resolved.
      </desc>
    </argument>
    <argument name="failCallbacks" type="Function">
      <desc>
        A function, or array of functions, called when the Deferred is rejected.
      </desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <signature>
    <added>1.7</added>
    <argument name="doneCallbacks" type="Function">
      <desc>
        A function, or array of functions, called when the Deferred is resolved.
      </desc>
    </argument>
    <argument name="failCallbacks" type="Function">
      <desc>
        A function, or array of functions, called when the Deferred is rejected.
      </desc>
    </argument>
    <argument name="progressCallbacks" type="Function" optional="true">
      <desc>
        A function, or array of functions, called when the Deferred notifies progress.
      </desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <desc> Add handlers to be called when the Deferred object is resolved or rejected. </desc>
  <longdesc> <p>All three arguments (including progressCallbacks, as of jQuery 1.7) can be either a single function or an array of functions. The arguments can also be <code>null</code> if no callback of that type is desired. Alternatively, use <code>.done()</code>, <code>.fail()</code> or <code>.progress()</code> to set only one type of callback. </p>
    <p>When the Deferred is resolved, the doneCallbacks are called. If the Deferred is instead rejected, the failCallbacks are called. As of jQuery 1.7, the <code>deferred.notify()</code> or <code>deferred.notifyWith()</code> methods can be called to invoke the progressCallbacks as many times as desired before the Deferred is resolved or rejected.</p>
    <p>Callbacks are executed in the order they were added. Since <code>deferred.then</code> returns the deferred object, other methods of the deferred object can be chained to this one, including additional <code>.then()</code> methods. For more information, see the documentation for <a href="http://api.jquery.com/category/deferred-object/">Deferred object</a>.</p> </longdesc>
   <example>
        <desc>Since the <a href="/jQuery.get"><code>jQuery.get</code></a> method returns a jqXHR object, which is derived from a Deferred object, we can attach handlers using the <code>.then</code> method.</desc>
<code><![CDATA[
$.get("test.php").then(
    function(){ alert("$.get succeeded"); },
    function(){ alert("$.get failed!"); }
);
]]></code>
    </example>
<category slug="deferred-object"/>
<category slug="version/1.5"/>
<category slug="version/1.7"/>
</entry>