<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry type="method" name="delay" return="jQuery">
  <title>.delay()</title>
  <signature>
    <added>1.4</added>
    <argument name="duration" type="Integer">
      <desc>An integer indicating the number of milliseconds to delay execution of the next item in the queue.</desc>
    </argument>
    <argument name="queueName" optional="true" type="String">
      <desc>A string containing the name of the queue. Defaults to <code>fx</code>, the standard effects queue.</desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <desc>Set a timer to delay execution of subsequent items in the queue.</desc>
  <longdesc>
    <p>Added to jQuery in version 1.4, the <code>.delay()</code> method allows us to delay the execution of functions that follow it in the queue. It can be used with the standard effects queue or with a custom queue. Only subsequent events in a queue are delayed; for example this will <em>not</em> delay the no-arguments forms of <code>.show()</code> or <code>.hide()</code>  which do not use the effects queue.</p>
    <p>Durations are given in milliseconds; higher values indicate slower animations, not faster ones. The strings <code>'fast'</code> and <code>'slow'</code> can be supplied to indicate durations of 200 and 600 milliseconds, respectively.</p>
    <p>Using the standard effects queue, we can, for example, set an 800-millisecond delay between the <code>.slideUp()</code> and <code>.fadeIn()</code> of <code>&lt;div id="foo"&gt;</code>:</p>
    <pre><code>$('#foo').slideUp(300).delay(800).fadeIn(400);</code></pre>
    <p>When this statement is executed, the element slides up for 300 milliseconds and then pauses for 800 milliseconds before fading in for 400 milliseconds.</p>
    <div class="warning">
      <p>
        <strong>The <code>.delay()</code> method is best for delaying between queued jQuery effects. Because it is limited&#x2014;it doesn't, for example, offer a way to cancel the delay&#x2014;<code>.delay()</code> is not a replacement for JavaScript's native <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en/DOM/window.setTimeout">setTimeout</a> function, which may be more appropriate for certain use cases.</strong>
      </p>
    </div>
  </longdesc>
  <example>
    <desc>Animate the hiding and showing of two divs, delaying the first before showing it.</desc>
    <css><![CDATA[
div { position: absolute; width: 60px; height: 60px; float: left; }
.first { background-color: #3f3; left: 0;}
.second { background-color: #33f; left: 80px;}
]]></css>
    <code><![CDATA[
    $("button").click(function() {
      $("div.first").slideUp(300).delay(800).fadeIn(400);
      $("div.second").slideUp(300).fadeIn(400);
    });]]></code>
    <html><![CDATA[
<p><button>Run</button></p>
<div class="first"></div>
<div class="second"></div>]]></html>
  </example>
  <category slug="effects/custom-effects"/>
  <category slug="version/1.4"/>
</entry>