<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry type="method" name="end" return="jQuery">
  <title>.end()</title>
  <signature>
    <added>1.0</added>
  </signature>
  <desc>End the most recent filtering operation in the current chain and return the set of matched elements to its previous state.</desc>
  <longdesc>
    <p>Most of jQuery's <a href="http://api.jquery.com/category/traversing">DOM traversal</a> methods operate on a jQuery object instance and produce a new one, matching a different set of DOM elements. When this happens, it is as if the new set of elements is pushed onto a stack that is maintained inside the object. Each successive filtering method pushes a new element set onto the stack. If we need an older element set, we can use <code>end()</code> to pop the sets back off of the stack.</p>
    <p>Suppose we have a couple short lists on a page:</p>
    <pre><code>
&lt;ul class="first"&gt;
  &lt;li class="foo"&gt;list item 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="bar"&gt;list item 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class="second"&gt;
  &lt;li class="foo"&gt;list item 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class="bar"&gt;list item 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</code></pre>
    <p>The <code>end()</code> method is useful primarily when exploiting jQuery's chaining properties. When not using chaining, we can usually just call up a previous object by variable name, so we don't need to manipulate the stack. With <code>end()</code>, though, we can string all the method calls together:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "ul.first" )
  .find( ".foo" )
    .css( "background-color", "red" )
  .end()
    .find( ".bar" )
  .css( "background-color", "green" );
    </code></pre>
    <p>This chain searches for items with the class <code>foo</code> within the first list only and turns their backgrounds red. Then <code>end()</code> returns the object to its state before the call to <code>find()</code>, so the second <code>find()</code> looks for '.bar' inside <code>&lt;ul class="first"&gt;</code>, not just inside that list's <code>&lt;li class="foo"&gt;</code>, and turns the matching elements' backgrounds green. The net result is that items 1 and 3 of the first list have a colored background, and none of the items from the second list do.</p>
    <p>A long jQuery chain can be visualized as a structured code block, with filtering methods providing the openings of nested blocks and <code>end()</code> methods closing them:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "ul.first" )
  .find( ".foo" )
    .css( "background-color", "red" )
  .end()
  .find( ".bar" )
    .css( "background-color", "green" )
  .end();
    </code></pre>
    <p>The last <code>end()</code> is unnecessary, as we are discarding the jQuery object immediately thereafter. However, when the code is written in this form, the <code>end()</code> provides visual symmetry and a sense of completion &#x2014;making the program, at least to the eyes of some developers, more readable, at the cost of a slight hit to performance as it is an additional function call.</p>
  </longdesc>
  <example>
    <desc>Selects all paragraphs, finds span elements inside these, and reverts the selection back to the paragraphs.</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
jQuery.fn.showTags = function( n ) {
  var tags = this.map(function() {
    return this.tagName;
  })
  .get()
  .join(", ");
  $( "b:eq( " + n + " )" ).text( tags );
  return this;
};

$( "p" )
  .showTags( 0 )
  .find( "span" )
    .showTags( 1 )
    .css( "background", "yellow" )
  .end()
  .showTags( 2 )
  .css( "font-style", "italic" );
]]></code>
    <css><![CDATA[
  p, div {
    margin: 1px;
    padding: 1px;
    font-weight: bold;
    font-size: 16px;
  }
  div {
    color: blue;
  }
  b {
    color: red;
  }
]]></css>
    <html><![CDATA[
<p>
  Hi there <span>how</span> are you <span>doing</span>?
</p>

<p>
  This <span>span</span> is one of
  several <span>spans</span> in this
  <span>sentence</span>.
</p>

<div>
  Tags in jQuery object initially: <b></b>
</div>

<div>
  Tags in jQuery object after find: <b></b>
</div>

<div>
  Tags in jQuery object after end: <b></b>
</div>
]]></html>
  </example>
  <example>
    <desc>Selects all paragraphs, finds span elements inside these, and reverts the selection back to the paragraphs.</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( "p" )
  .find( "span" )
  .end()
  .css( "border", "2px red solid" );
]]></code>
    <css><![CDATA[
  p {
    margin: 10px;
    padding: 10px;
  }
]]></css>
    <html><![CDATA[
<p><span>Hello</span>, how are you?</p>
]]></html>
  </example>
  <category slug="traversing/miscellaneous-traversal"/>
  <category slug="version/1.0"/>
</entry>
