<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry type="method" name="eq" return="jQuery">
  <title>.eq()</title>
  <signature>
    <added>1.1.2</added>
    <argument name="index" type="Integer">
      <desc>An integer indicating the 0-based position of the element. </desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <signature>
    <added>1.4</added>
    <argument name="-index" type="Integer">
      <desc>An integer indicating the position of the element, counting backwards from the last element in the set. </desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <desc>Reduce the set of matched elements to the one at the specified index.</desc>
  <longdesc>
    <p>Given a jQuery object that represents a set of DOM elements, the <code>.eq()</code> method constructs a new jQuery object from one element within that set. The supplied index identifies the position of this element in the set. </p>
    <p>Consider a page with a simple list on it:</p>
    <pre><code>
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    </code></pre>
    <p>We can apply this method to the set of list items:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "li" ).eq( 2 ).css( "background-color", "red" );
    </code></pre>
    <p>The result of this call is a red background for item 3. Note that the supplied index is zero-based, and refers to the position of the element within the jQuery object, not within the DOM tree.</p>
    <p>Providing a negative number indicates a position starting from the end of the set, rather than the beginning. For example:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "li" ).eq( -2 ).css( "background-color", "red" );
    </code></pre>
    <p>This time list item 4 is turned red, since it is two from the end of the set.</p>
    <p>If an element cannot be found at the specified zero-based index, the method constructs a new jQuery object with an empty set and a <code>length</code> property of 0. </p>
    <pre><code>
$( "li" ).eq( 5 ).css( "background-color", "red" );
    </code></pre>
    <p>Here, none of the list items is turned red, since <code>.eq( 5 )</code> indicates the sixth of five list items.</p>
  </longdesc>
  <example>
    <desc>Turn the div with index 2 blue by adding an appropriate class.</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( "body" ).find( "div" ).eq( 2 ).addClass( "blue" );
]]></code>
    <css><![CDATA[
  div {
    width: 60px;
    height: 60px;
    margin: 10px;
    float: left;
    border: 2px solid blue;
  }
  .blue {
    background: blue;
  }
]]></css>
    <html><![CDATA[
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
]]></html>
  </example>
  <category slug="traversing/filtering"/>
  <category slug="version/1.1.2"/>
</entry>
