<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry type="method" name="fadeToggle" return="jQuery">
  <title>.fadeToggle()</title>
  <desc>Display or hide the matched elements by animating their opacity.</desc>
  <signature>
    <added>1.4.4</added>
    <xi:include href="../includes/duration-argument.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"/>
    <xi:include href="../includes/easing-argument.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"/>
    <xi:include href="../includes/complete-argument.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"/>
  </signature>
  <signature>
    <added>1.4.4</added>
    <xi:include href="../includes/options-argument.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"/>
  </signature>

  <longdesc>
    <p>The <code>.fadeToggle()</code> method animates the opacity of the matched elements. When called on a visible element, the element's <code>display</code> style property is set to <code>none</code> once the opacity reaches 0, so the element no longer affects the layout of the page.</p>
    <p>Durations are given in milliseconds; higher values indicate slower animations, not faster ones. The strings <code>'fast'</code> and <code>'slow'</code> can be supplied to indicate durations of <code>200</code> and <code>600</code> milliseconds, respectively.</p>
    <h4 id="easing">Easing</h4>
    <p>The string representing an easing function specifies the speed at which the animation progresses at different points within the animation. The only easing implementations in the jQuery library are the default, called <code>swing</code>, and one that progresses at a constant pace, called <code>linear</code>. More easing functions are available with the use of plug-ins, most notably the <a href="http://jqueryui.com">jQuery UI suite</a>.</p>
    <h4 id="callback-function">Callback Function</h4>
    <p>If supplied, the callback is fired once the animation is complete. This can be useful for stringing different animations together in sequence. The callback is not sent any arguments, but <code>this</code> is set to the DOM element being animated. If multiple elements are animated, it is important to note that the callback is executed once per matched element, not once for the animation as a whole.</p>
    <p><strong>As of jQuery 1.6</strong>, the <code><a href="/promise/">.promise()</a></code> method can be used in conjunction with the <code><a href="/deferred.done/">deferred.done()</a></code> method to execute a single callback for the animation as a whole when <em>all</em> matching elements have completed their animations ( See the <a href="/promise/#example-1">example for .promise()</a> ).  </p>
  </longdesc>
  <note id="jquery.fx.off" type="additional" data-title=".fadeToggle()"/>
  <example>
    <desc>Fades first paragraph in or out, completing the animation within 600 milliseconds and using a linear easing. Fades last paragraph in or out for 200 milliseconds, inserting a "finished" message upon completion. </desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( "button:first" ).click(function() {
  $( "p:first" ).fadeToggle( "slow", "linear" );
});
$( "button:last" ).click(function() {
  $( "p:last" ).fadeToggle( "fast", function() {
    $( "#log" ).append( "<div>finished</div>" );
  });
});
]]></code>
    <html><![CDATA[
<button>fadeToggle p1</button>
<button>fadeToggle p2</button>
<p>This paragraph has a slow, linear fade.</p>
<p>This paragraph has a fast animation.</p>
<div id="log"></div>
]]></html>
  </example>
  <category slug="effects"/>
  <category slug="effects/fading"/>
  <category slug="version/1.4.4"/>
</entry>
