<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry type="method" name="filter" return="jQuery">
  <title>.filter()</title>
  <signature>
    <added>1.0</added>
    <argument name="selector" type="Selector">
      <desc>A string containing a selector expression to match the current set of elements against.</desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <signature>
    <added>1.0</added>
    <argument name="function(index)" type="Function">
      <desc>A function used as a test for each element in the set. <code>this</code> is the current DOM element.</desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <signature>
    <added>1.4</added>
    <argument name="element" type="Element">
      <desc>An element to match the current set of elements against.</desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <signature>
    <added>1.4</added>
    <argument name="jQuery object" type="Object">
      <desc>An existing jQuery object to match the current set of elements against.</desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <desc>Reduce the set of matched elements to those that match the selector or pass the function's test. </desc>
  <longdesc><p>Given a jQuery object that represents a set of DOM elements, the <code>.filter()</code> method constructs a new jQuery object from a subset of the matching elements. The supplied selector is tested against each element; all elements matching the selector will be included in the result.</p><p>Consider a page with a simple list on it:</p>
    <pre><code>
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    </code></pre>
    <p>We can apply this method to the set of list items:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "li" ).filter( ":even" ).css( "background-color", "red" );
    </code></pre>
    <p>The result of this call is a red background for items 1, 3, and 5, as they match the selector (recall that <code>:even</code> and <code>:odd</code> use 0-based indexing).</p>
    <h4 id="using-filter-function">Using a Filter Function</h4>
    <p>The second form of this method allows us to filter elements against a function rather than a selector. For each element, if the function returns <code>true</code> (or a "truthy" value), the element will be included in the filtered set; otherwise, it will be excluded. Suppose we have a somewhat more involved HTML snippet:</p>
    <pre><code>
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;list&lt;/strong&gt; item 1 -
    one strong tag&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;list&lt;/strong&gt; item &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; -
    two &lt;span&gt;strong tags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;list item 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    </code></pre>
    <p>We can select the list items, then filter them based on their contents:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "li" )
  .filter(function( index ) {
    return $( "strong", this ).length == 1;
  })
  .css( "background-color", "red" );
    </code></pre>
    <p>This code will alter the first list item only, as it contains exactly one <code>&lt;strong&gt;</code> tag. Within the filter function, <code>this</code> refers to each DOM element in turn. The parameter passed to the function tells us the index of that DOM element within the set matched by the jQuery object.</p>
    <p>We can also take advantage of the <code>index</code> passed through the function, which indicates the 0-based position of the element within the unfiltered set of matched elements:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "li" )
  .filter(function( index ) {
    return index % 3 == 2;
  })
  .css( "background-color", "red" );
    </code></pre>
    <p>This alteration to the code will cause the third and sixth list items to be highlighted, as it uses the modulus operator (<code>%</code>) to select every item with an <code>index</code> value that, when divided by 3, has a remainder of <code>2</code>.</p>
  </longdesc>
  <example>
    <desc>Change the color of all divs; then add a border to those with a "middle" class.</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
  $( "div" )
    .css( "background", "#c8ebcc" )
    .filter( ".middle" )
    .css( "border-color", "red" );
]]></code>
    <css><![CDATA[
  div {
    width: 60px;
    height: 60px;
    margin: 5px;
    float: left;
    border: 2px white solid;
  }
]]></css>
    <html><![CDATA[
<div></div>
<div class="middle"></div>
<div class="middle"></div>
<div class="middle"></div>
<div class="middle"></div>
<div></div>
]]></html>
  </example>
  <example>
    <desc>Change the color of all divs; then add a border to the second one (index == 1) and the div with an id of "fourth."</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( "div" )
  .css( "background", "#b4b0da" )
  .filter(function( index ) {
    return index == 1 || $( this ).attr( "id" ) == "fourth";
  })
  .css( "border", "3px double red" );
]]></code>
    <css><![CDATA[
  div {
    width: 60px;
    height: 60px;
    margin: 5px;
    float: left;
    border: 3px white solid;
  }
]]></css>
    <html><![CDATA[
<div id="first"></div>
<div id="second"></div>
<div id="third"></div>
<div id="fourth"></div>
<div id="fifth"></div>
<div id="sixth"></div>
]]></html>
  </example>
  <example>
    <desc>Select all divs and filter the selection with a DOM element, keeping only the one with an id of "unique".</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( "div" ).filter( document.getElementById( "unique" ) );
]]></code>
  </example>
  <example>
    <desc>Select all divs and filter the selection with a jQuery object, keeping only the one with an id of "unique".</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( "div" ).filter( $( "#unique" ) );
]]></code>
  </example>
  <category slug="traversing/filtering"/>
  <category slug="version/1.0"/>
  <category slug="version/1.4"/>
</entry>
