<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry type="property" name="jQuery.cssHooks" return="Object">
  <title>jQuery.cssHooks</title>
  <signature>
    <added>1.4.3</added>
  </signature>
  <desc>Hook directly into jQuery to override how particular CSS properties are retrieved or set, normalize CSS property naming, or create custom properties.</desc>
  <longdesc>
    <p>The <code>$.cssHooks</code> object provides a way to define functions for getting and setting particular CSS values. It can also be used to create new cssHooks for normalizing CSS3 features such as box shadows and gradients. </p>
    <p>For example, some versions of Webkit-based browsers require <code>-webkit-border-radius</code> to set the <code>border-radius</code> on an element, while earlier Firefox versions require <code>-moz-border-radius</code>. A css hook can normalize these vendor-prefixed properties to let <code>.css()</code> accept a single, standard property name (<code>border-radius</code>, or with DOM property syntax, <code>borderRadius</code>).</p>
    <p>In addition to providing fine-grained control over how specific style properties are handled, <code>$.cssHooks</code> also extends the set of properties available to the <code>.animate()</code> method.</p>
    <p>Defining a new css hook is straight-forward. The skeleton template below can serve as a guide to creating your own. </p>
    <pre><code>
(function( $ ) {
  // First, check to see if cssHooks are supported
  if ( !$.cssHooks ) {
    // If not, output an error message
    throw("jQuery 1.4.3 or above is required for this plugin to work");
    return;
  }

  // Wrap in a document ready call, because jQuery writes
  // cssHooks at this time and will blow away your functions
  // if they exist.
  $(function () {
    $.cssHooks[ "someCSSProp" ] = {
      get: function( elem, computed, extra ) {
        // Handle getting the CSS property
      },
      set: function( elem, value ) {
        // Handle setting the CSS value
      }
    };
  });
})( jQuery );
    </code></pre>
    <h4 id="feature-testing">Feature Testing</h4>
    <p>Before normalizing a vendor-specific CSS property, first determine whether the browser supports the standard property or a vendor-prefixed variation. For example, to check for support of the <code>border-radius</code> property, see if any variation is a member of a temporary element's <code>style</code> object.</p>
    <pre><code>
(function( $ ) {
  function styleSupport( prop ) {
    var vendorProp, supportedProp,
      // Capitalize first character of the prop to test vendor prefix
      capProp = prop.charAt( 0 ).toUpperCase() + prop.slice( 1 ),
      prefixes = [ "Moz", "Webkit", "O", "ms" ],
      div = document.createElement( "div" );

    if ( prop in div.style ) {
      // Browser supports standard CSS property name
      supportedProp = prop;
    } else {
      // Otherwise test support for vendor-prefixed property names
      for ( var i = 0; i &lt; prefixes.length; i++ ) {
        vendorProp = prefixes[ i ] + capProp;
        if ( vendorProp in div.style ) {
          supportedProp = vendorProp;
          break;
        }
      }
    }
    // Avoid memory leak in IE
    div = null;
    // Add property to $.support so it can be accessed elsewhere
    $.support[ prop ] = supportedProp;
    return supportedProp;
  }
  // Call the function, e.g. testing for "border-radius" support:
  styleSupport( "borderRadius" );
})( jQuery );
    </code></pre>
    <h4 id="defining-complete-csshook">Defining a complete css hook</h4>
    <p>To define a complete css hook, combine the support test with a filled-out version of the skeleton template provided in the first example:</p>
    <pre><code>
(function( $ ) {
  if ( !$.cssHooks ) {
    throw( "jQuery 1.4.3+ is needed for this plugin to work" );
    return;
  }

  function styleSupport( prop ) {
    var vendorProp, supportedProp,
      capProp = prop.charAt( 0 ).toUpperCase() + prop.slice( 1 ),
      prefixes = [ "Moz", "Webkit", "O", "ms" ],
      div = document.createElement( "div" );

    if ( prop in div.style ) {
      supportedProp = prop;
    } else {
      for ( var i = 0; i &lt; prefixes.length; i++ ) {
        vendorProp = prefixes[ i ] + capProp;
        if ( vendorProp in div.style ) {
          supportedProp = vendorProp;
          break;
        }
      }
    }

    div = null;
    $.support[ prop ] = supportedProp;
    return supportedProp;
  }
  var borderRadius = styleSupport( "borderRadius" );
  // Set cssHooks only for browsers that
  // support a vendor-prefixed border radius
  if ( borderRadius &amp;&amp; borderRadius !== "borderRadius" ) {
    $.cssHooks.borderRadius = {
      get: function( elem, computed, extra ) {
        return $.css( elem, borderRadius );
      },
      set: function( elem, value) {
        elem.style[ borderRadius ] = value;
      }
    };
  }
})( jQuery );
    </code></pre>
    <p>You can then set the border radius in a supported browser using either the DOM (camelCased) style or the CSS (hyphenated) style:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "#element" ).css( "borderRadius", "10px" );
$( "#another" ).css( "border-radius", "20px" );
    </code></pre>
    <p>If the browser lacks support for any form of the CSS property, vendor-prefixed or not, the style is not applied to the element. However, if the browser supports a proprietary alternative, it can be applied to the cssHooks instead. </p>
    <pre><code>
 (function( $ ) {
  // Feature test for support of a CSS property
  // and a proprietary alternative
  // ...
 if ( $.support.someCSSProp &amp;&amp; $.support.someCSSProp !== "someCSSProp" ) {
    // Set cssHooks for browsers that
    // support only a vendor-prefixed someCSSProp
    $.cssHooks.someCSSProp = {
      get: function( elem, computed, extra ) {
        return $.css( elem, $.support.someCSSProp );
      },
      set: function( elem, value) {
        elem.style[ $.support.someCSSProp ] = value;
      }
    };
  } else if ( supportsProprietaryAlternative ) {
    $.cssHooks.someCSSProp = {
      get: function( elem, computed, extra ) {
        // Handle crazy conversion from the proprietary alternative
      },
      set: function( elem, value ) {
        // Handle crazy conversion to the proprietary alternative
      }
    }
  }
})( jQuery );
    </code></pre>
    <h4 id="special-units">Special units</h4>
    <p>By default, jQuery adds a "px" unit to the values passed to the <code>.css()</code> method. This behavior can be prevented by adding the property to the <code>jQuery.cssNumber</code> object</p>
    <pre><code>
$.cssNumber[ "someCSSProp" ] = true;
    </code></pre>
    <h4 id="animating">Animating with cssHooks</h4>
    <p>A css hook can also hook into jQuery's animation mechanism by adding a property to the <code>jQuery.fx.step</code> object:</p>
    <pre><code>
  $.fx.step[ "someCSSProp" ] = function( fx ) {
  $.cssHooks[ "someCSSProp" ].set( fx.elem, fx.now + fx.unit );
};
    </code></pre>
    <p>Note that this works best for simple numeric-value animations. More custom code may be required depending on the CSS property, the type of value it returns, and the animation's complexity.</p>
  </longdesc>
  <category slug="css"/>
  <category slug="version/1.4.3"/>
</entry>
