<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry type="method" name="jQuery.ajaxPrefilter" return="undefined">
  <title>jQuery.ajaxPrefilter()</title>
  <desc>Handle custom Ajax options or modify existing options before each request is sent and before they are processed by <code>$.ajax()</code>.</desc>
  <signature>
    <added>1.5</added>
    <argument name="dataTypes" optional="true" type="String">
      <desc>An optional string containing one or more space-separated dataTypes</desc>
    </argument>
    <argument name="handler(options, originalOptions, jqXHR)" type="Function">
      <desc>A handler to set default values for future Ajax requests.</desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <longdesc>
    <p>A typical prefilter registration using <code>$.ajaxPrefilter()</code> looks like this:</p>
    <pre><code>
$.ajaxPrefilter( function( options, originalOptions, jqXHR ) {
  // Modify options, control originalOptions, store jqXHR, etc
});
    </code></pre>
    <p>where:</p>
    <ul>
      <li><code>options</code> are the request options</li>
      <li><code>originalOptions</code> are the options as provided to the ajax method, unmodified and, thus, without defaults from <code>ajaxSettings</code></li>
      <li><code>jqXHR</code> is the jqXHR object of the request</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Prefilters are a perfect fit when custom options need to be handled.  Given the following code, for example, a call to <code>$.ajax()</code> would automatically abort a request to the same URL if the custom <code>abortOnRetry</code> option is set to <code>true</code>:</p>
    <pre><code>
var currentRequests = {};

$.ajaxPrefilter(function( options, originalOptions, jqXHR ) {
  if ( options.abortOnRetry ) {
    if ( currentRequests[ options.url ] ) {
      currentRequests[ options.url ].abort();
    }
    currentRequests[ options.url ] = jqXHR;
  }
});
    </code></pre>
    <p>Prefilters can also be used to modify existing options. For example, the following proxies cross-domain requests through http://mydomain.net/proxy/:</p>
    <pre><code>
$.ajaxPrefilter( function( options ) {
  if ( options.crossDomain ) {
    options.url = "http://mydomain.net/proxy/" + encodeURIComponent( options.url );
    options.crossDomain = false;
  }
});
    </code></pre>
    <p>If the optional <code>dataTypes</code> argument is supplied, the prefilter will be only be applied to requests with the indicated dataTypes. For example, the following only applies the given prefilter to JSON and script requests:</p>
    <pre><code>
$.ajaxPrefilter( "json script", function( options, originalOptions, jqXHR ) {
  // Modify options, control originalOptions, store jqXHR, etc
});
    </code></pre>
    <p>The <code>$.ajaxPrefilter()</code> method can also redirect a request to another dataType by returning that dataType. For example, the following sets a request as "script" if the URL has some specific properties defined in a custom <code>isActuallyScript()</code> function:</p>
    <pre><code>
$.ajaxPrefilter(function( options ) {
  if ( isActuallyScript( options.url ) ) {
    return "script";
  }
});
    </code></pre>
    <p>This would ensure not only that the request is considered "script" but also that all the prefilters specifically attached to the script dataType would be applied to it.</p>
  </longdesc>
  <category slug="ajax/low-level-interface"/>
  <category slug="version/1.5"/>
</entry>
