<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry type="method" name="jQuery.ajaxSetup" return="">
  <title>jQuery.ajaxSetup()</title>
  <signature>
    <added>1.1</added>
    <argument name="options" type="PlainObject">
      <desc>A set of key/value pairs that configure the default Ajax request. All options are optional. </desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <desc>Set default values for future Ajax requests. Its use is not recommended.</desc>
  <longdesc>
    <p>For details on the settings available for <code>$.ajaxSetup()</code>, see <code><a href="/jQuery.ajax/">$.ajax()</a></code>. </p>
    <p>All subsequent Ajax calls using any function will use the new settings, unless overridden by the individual calls, until the next invocation of <code>$.ajaxSetup()</code>.</p>
    <p><strong>Note:</strong> The settings specified here will affect <em>all</em> calls to <code>$.ajax</code> or AJAX-based derivatives such as <code>$.get()</code>. This can cause undesirable behavior since other callers (for example, plugins) may be expecting the normal default settings. For that reason we <em>strongly recommend against using this API</em>. Instead, set the options explicitly in the call or define a simple plugin to do so.</p>
    <p>For example, the following sets a default for the <code>url</code> parameter before pinging the server repeatedly:</p>
    <pre><code>
$.ajaxSetup({
  url: "ping.php"
});
    </code></pre>
    <p>Now each time an Ajax request is made, the "ping.php" URL will be used automatically:</p>
    <pre><code>
$.ajax({
  // url not set here; uses ping.php
  data: { "name": "Dan" }
});
    </code></pre>
    <div class="warning">
      <p>Note: Global callback functions should be set with their respective global Ajax event handler methods&#x2014;<code><a href="/ajaxStart/">.ajaxStart()</a></code>, <code><a href="/ajaxStop/">.ajaxStop()</a></code>, <code><a href="/ajaxComplete/">.ajaxComplete()</a></code>, <code><a href="/ajaxError/">.ajaxError()</a></code>, <code><a href="/ajaxSuccess/">.ajaxSuccess()</a></code>, <code><a href="/ajaxSend/">.ajaxSend()</a></code>&#x2014;rather than within the <code>options</code> object for <code>$.ajaxSetup()</code>.</p>
    </div>
  </longdesc>
  <example>
    <desc>Sets the defaults for Ajax requests to the url "/xmlhttp/", disables global handlers and uses POST instead of GET. The following Ajax requests then sends some data without having to set anything else.</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$.ajaxSetup({
  url: "/xmlhttp/",
  global: false,
  type: "POST"
});
$.ajax({ data: myData });
]]></code>
  </example>
  <category slug="ajax/low-level-interface"/>
  <category slug="version/1.1"/>
</entry>
