<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entries deprecated="1.3" removed="1.9">
  <entry type="property" name="jQuery.browser" return="PlainObject" deprecated="1.3" removed="1.9">
    <title>jQuery.browser</title>
    <signature>
      <added>1.0</added>
    </signature>
    <desc>Contains flags for the useragent, read from navigator.userAgent. <strong>This property was removed in jQuery 1.9</strong> and is available only through the jQuery.migrate plugin. Please try to use feature detection instead.</desc>
    <longdesc>
      <p>The <code>$.browser</code> property provides information about the web browser that is accessing the page, as reported by the browser itself. It contains flags for each of the four most prevalent browser classes (Internet Explorer, Mozilla, Webkit, and Opera) as well as version information.</p>
      <p>Available flags are:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>webkit (as of jQuery 1.4)</li>
        <li>safari (deprecated)</li>
        <li>opera</li>
        <li>msie</li>
        <li>mozilla</li>
      </ul>
      <p>This property is available immediately. It is therefore safe to use it to determine whether or not to call <code>$(document).ready()</code>.
    The <code>$.browser</code> property is deprecated in jQuery 1.3, and its functionality may be moved to a team-supported plugin in a future release of jQuery.</p>
      <p>Because <code>$.browser</code> uses <code>navigator.userAgent</code> to determine the platform, it is vulnerable to spoofing by the user or misrepresentation by the browser itself. It is always best to avoid browser-specific code entirely where possible. The <code><a href="/jQuery.support/">$.support</a></code> property is available for detection of support for particular features rather than relying on <code>$.browser</code>. </p>
    </longdesc>
    <example>
      <desc>Show the browser info.</desc>
      <code><![CDATA[
jQuery.each(jQuery.browser, function( i, val ) {
  $( "<div>" + i + " : <span>" + val + "</span>" )
  .appendTo( document.body );
});
]]></code>
    </example>
    <example>
      <desc>Return true if the current useragent is some version of Microsoft's Internet Explorer. <strong>Will not work in jQuery 1.9 or later</strong> unless the <a href="https://github.com/jquery/jquery-migrate/#readme">jQuery Migrate</a> plugin is included.</desc>
      <code><![CDATA[
$.browser.msie;
]]></code>
    </example>
    <example>
      <desc>Alert "this is WebKit!" only for WebKit browsers. <strong>Will not work in jQuery 1.9 or later</strong> unless the <a href="https://github.com/jquery/jquery-migrate/#readme">jQuery Migrate</a> plugin is included.</desc>
      <code><![CDATA[
  if ( $.browser.webkit ) {
    alert( "this is webkit!" );
  }
]]></code>
    </example>
    <category slug="properties/global-jquery-object-properties"/>
    <category slug="utilities"/>
    <category slug="version/1.0"/>
    <category slug="version/1.1.3"/>
    <category slug="deprecated/deprecated-1.3"/>
  </entry>
  <entry type="property" name="jQuery.browser.version" return="String" deprecated="1.3" removed="1.9">
    <signature>
      <added>1.1.3</added>
    </signature>
    <desc>The version number of the rendering engine for the user's browser. <strong>This property was removed in jQuery 1.9</strong> and is available only through the jQuery.migrate plugin.</desc>
    <longdesc>
      <p>Here are some typical results:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Internet Explorer: 6.0, 7.0, 8.0</li>
        <li>Mozilla/Firefox/Flock/Camino: 1.7.12, 1.8.1.3, 1.9</li>
        <li>Opera: 10.06, 11.01</li>
        <li>Safari/Webkit: 312.8, 418.9</li>
      </ul>
      <p>Note that IE8 claims to be 7 in Compatibility View.</p>
    </longdesc>
    <example>
      <desc>Return the version number of the rendering engine used by the user's current browser. For example, FireFox 4 returns 2.0 (the version of the Gecko rendering engine it utilizes). <strong>Will not work in jQuery 1.9 or later</strong> unless the <a href="https://github.com/jquery/jquery-migrate/#readme">jQuery Migrate</a> plugin is included.</desc>
      <code><![CDATA[
$( "p" ).html( "The version # of the browser's rendering engine is: <span>" +
  $.browser.version + "</span>" );
]]></code>
    </example>
    <example>
      <desc>Alert the version of IE's rendering engine that is being used. <strong>Will not work in jQuery 1.9 or later</strong> unless the <a href="https://github.com/jquery/jquery-migrate/#readme">jQuery Migrate</a> plugin is included.</desc>
      <code><![CDATA[
if ( $.browser.msie ) {
  alert( $.browser.version );
}
]]></code>
    </example>
    <category slug="properties/global-jquery-object-properties"/>
    <category slug="utilities"/>
    <category slug="version/1.0"/>
    <category slug="version/1.1.3"/>
    <category slug="deprecated/deprecated-1.3"/>
    <category slug="removed"/>
  </entry>
</entries>
