<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry name="jQuery.Deferred" type="method" return="Deferred">
  <title>jQuery.Deferred()</title>
  <signature>
    <added>1.5</added>
    <argument name="beforeStart" type="Function" optional="true">
      <desc>
        A function that is called just before the constructor returns.
      </desc>
      <argument name="deferred" type="Deferred">
        <desc>
          The constructed Deferred object.
        </desc>
      </argument>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <desc> A constructor function that returns a chainable utility object with methods to register multiple callbacks into callback queues, invoke callback queues, and relay the success or failure state of any synchronous or asynchronous function.</desc>
  <longdesc>
    <p>The <code>jQuery.Deferred()</code> constructor creates a new Deferred object. The <code>new</code> operator is optional.</p>
    <p>The <code>jQuery.Deferred</code> method can be passed an optional function, which is called just before the constructor returns and is passed the constructed <code>deferred</code> object as both the <code>this</code> object and as the first argument to the function. The called function can attach callbacks using <a href="/deferred.then/"><code>deferred.then()</code></a>, for example.</p>
    <p>A Deferred object starts in the <em>pending</em> state. Any callbacks added to the object with <a href="/deferred.then/"><code>deferred.then()</code></a>, <a href="/deferred.always/"><code>deferred.always()</code></a>, <a href="/deferred.done/"><code>deferred.done()</code></a>, or <a href="/deferred.fail/"><code>deferred.fail()</code></a> are queued to be executed later. Calling <a href="/deferred.resolve/"><code>deferred.resolve()</code></a> or <a href="/deferred.resolveWith/"><code>deferred.resolveWith()</code></a> transitions the Deferred into the <em>resolved</em> state and immediately executes any <code>doneCallbacks</code> that are set. Calling <a href="/deferred.reject/"><code>deferred.reject()</code></a> or <a href="/deferred.rejectWith/"><code>deferred.rejectWith()</code></a> transitions the Deferred into the <em>rejected</em> state and immediately executes any <code>failCallbacks</code> that are set. Once the object has entered the resolved or rejected state, it stays in that state. Callbacks can still be added to the resolved or rejected Deferred — they will execute immediately.</p>
    <h4>
      Enhanced Callbacks with jQuery Deferred
    </h4>
    <p>In JavaScript it is common to invoke functions that optionally accept callbacks that are called within that function. For example, in versions prior to jQuery 1.5, asynchronous processes such as <code>jQuery.ajax()</code> accept callbacks to be invoked some time in the near-future upon success, error, and completion of the ajax request.</p>
    <p><code>jQuery.Deferred()</code> introduces several enhancements to the way callbacks are managed and invoked. In particular, <code>jQuery.Deferred()</code> provides flexible ways to provide multiple callbacks, and these callbacks can be invoked regardless of whether the original callback dispatch has already occurred. jQuery Deferred is based on the <a href="http://wiki.commonjs.org/wiki/Promises/A">CommonJS Promises/A</a> design.</p>
    <p>One model for understanding Deferred is to think of it as a chain-aware function wrapper. The <a href="/deferred.then/"><code>deferred.then()</code></a>, <a href="/deferred.always/"><code>deferred.always()</code></a>, <a href="/deferred.done/"><code>deferred.done()</code></a>, and <a href="/deferred.fail/"><code>deferred.fail()</code></a> methods specify the functions to be called and the <a href="/deferred.resolve/"><code>deferred.resolve(args)</code></a> or <a href="/deferred.reject/"><code>deferred.reject(args)</code></a> methods "call" the functions with the arguments you supply. Once the Deferred has been resolved or rejected it stays in that state; a second call to <code>deferred.resolve()</code>, for example, is ignored. If more functions are added by <code>deferred.then()</code>, for example, after the Deferred is resolved, they are called immediately with the arguments previously provided.</p>
    <p>In most cases where a jQuery API call returns a Deferred or Deferred-compatible object, such as <a href="/jQuery.ajax/"><code>jQuery.ajax()</code></a> or <a href="/jQuery.when/"><code>jQuery.when()</code></a>, you will only want to use the <a href="/deferred.then/"><code>deferred.then()</code></a>, <a href="/deferred.done/"><code>deferred.done()</code></a>, and <a href="/deferred.fail/"><code>deferred.fail()</code></a> methods to add callbacks to the Deferred's queues. The internals of the API call or code that created the Deferred will invoke <a href="/deferred.resolve/"><code>deferred.resolve()</code></a> or <a href="/deferred.reject/"><code>deferred.reject()</code></a> on the deferred at some point, causing the appropriate callbacks to run.</p>
  </longdesc>
  <category slug="deferred-object"/>
  <category slug="version/1.5"/>
</entry>
