<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry type="method" name="load" return="jQuery">
  <title>.load()</title>
  <signature>
    <added>1.0</added>
    <argument name="url" type="String">
      <desc>A string containing the URL to which the request is sent.</desc>
    </argument>
    <argument name="data" optional="true">
      <type name="PlainObject"/>
      <type name="String"/>
      <desc>A plain object or string that is sent to the server with the request.</desc>
    </argument>
    <argument name="complete(responseText, textStatus, XMLHttpRequest)" type="Function" optional="true">
      <desc>A callback function that is executed when the request completes.</desc>
    </argument>
  </signature>
  <desc>Load data from the server and place the returned HTML into the matched element.</desc>
  <longdesc>
    <div class="warning">
      <p>Note: The event handling suite also has a method named <code><a href="/load-event/">.load()</a></code>. jQuery determines which method to fire based on the set of arguments passed to it.</p>
    </div>
    <p>This method is the simplest way to fetch data from the server. It is roughly equivalent to <code>$.get(url, data, success)</code> except that it is a method rather than global function and it has an implicit callback function.  When a successful response is detected (i.e. when <code>textStatus</code> is "success" or "notmodified"), <code>.load()</code> sets the HTML contents of the matched element to the returned data. This means that most uses of the method can be quite simple:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "#result" ).load( "ajax/test.html" );
    </code></pre>
    <p>If no element is matched by the selector — in this case, if the document does not contain an element with id="result" — the Ajax request will <em>not</em> be sent.</p>
    <h4 id="callback-function">Callback Function</h4>
    <p>If a "complete" callback is provided, it is executed after post-processing and HTML insertion has been performed. The callback is fired once for each element in the jQuery collection, and <code>this</code> is set to each DOM element in turn.</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "#result" ).load( "ajax/test.html", function() {
  alert( "Load was performed." );
});
    </code></pre>
    <p>In the two examples above, if the current document does not contain an element with an ID of "result," the <code>.load()</code> method is not executed.</p>
    <h4 id="request-method">Request Method</h4>
    <p>The POST method is used if data is provided as an object; otherwise, GET is assumed.</p>
    <h4 id="loading-page-fragments">Loading Page Fragments</h4>
    <p>The <code>.load()</code> method, unlike <code><a href="/jQuery.get/">$.get()</a></code>, allows us to specify a portion of the remote document to be inserted. This is achieved with a special syntax for the <code>url</code> parameter. If one or more space characters are included in the string, the portion of the string following the first space is assumed to be a jQuery selector that determines the content to be loaded.   </p>
    <p>We could modify the example above to use only part of the document that is fetched:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "#result" ).load( "ajax/test.html #container" );
    </code></pre>
    <p>When this method executes, it retrieves the content of <code>ajax/test.html</code>, but then jQuery parses the returned document to find the element with an ID of <code>container</code>. This element, along with its contents, is inserted into the element with an ID of <code>result</code>, and the rest of the retrieved document is discarded.</p>
    <p>jQuery uses the browser's <code>.innerHTML</code> property to parse the retrieved document and insert it into the current document. During this process, browsers often filter elements from the document such as <code>&lt;html&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;title&gt;</code>, or <code>&lt;head&gt;</code> elements. As a result, the elements retrieved by <code>.load()</code> may not be exactly the same as if the document were retrieved directly by the browser.</p>
    <h4 id="script-execution">Script Execution</h4>
    <p> When calling <code>.load()</code> using a URL without a suffixed selector expression, the content is passed to <code>.html()</code> prior to scripts being removed. This executes the script blocks before they are discarded. If <code>.load()</code> is called with a selector expression appended to the URL, however, the scripts are stripped out prior to the DOM being updated, and thus are <em>not</em> executed. An example of both cases can be seen below:
</p>
    <p>Here, any JavaScript loaded into <code>#a</code> as a part of the document will successfully execute.</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "#a" ).load( "article.html" );
    </code></pre>
    <p>However, in the following case, script blocks in the document being loaded into <code>#b</code> are stripped out and not executed:</p>
    <pre><code>
$( "#b" ).load( "article.html #target" );
</code></pre>
  </longdesc>
  <note id="same-origin-policy" type="additional"/>
  <example>
    <desc>Load the main page's footer navigation into an ordered list.</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( "#new-nav" ).load( "/ #jq-footerNavigation li" );
]]></code>
    <css><![CDATA[
  body {
    font-size: 12px;
    font-family: Arial;
  }
]]></css>
    <html><![CDATA[
<b>Footer navigation:</b>
<ol id="new-nav"></ol>
]]></html>
  </example>
  <example>
    <desc>Display a notice if the Ajax request encounters an error.</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( "#success" ).load( "/not-here.php", function( response, status, xhr ) {
  if ( status == "error" ) {
    var msg = "Sorry but there was an error: ";
    $( "#error" ).html( msg + xhr.status + " " + xhr.statusText );
  }
});
]]></code>
    <css><![CDATA[
  body {
    font-size: 12px;
    font-family: Arial;
  }
]]></css>
    <html><![CDATA[
<b>Successful Response (should be blank):</b>
<div id="success"></div>
<b>Error Response:</b>
<div id="error"></div>
]]></html>
  </example>
  <example>
    <desc>Load the feeds.html file into the div with the ID of feeds.</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( "#feeds" ).load( "feeds.html" );
]]></code>
    <results><![CDATA[
<div id="feeds"><b>45</b> feeds found.</div>
]]></results>
  </example>
  <example>
    <desc>pass arrays of data to the server.</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( "#objectID" ).load( "test.php", { "choices[]": [ "Jon", "Susan" ] } );
]]></code>
  </example>
  <example>
    <desc>Same as above, but will POST the additional parameters to the server and a callback that is executed when the server is finished responding.</desc>
    <code><![CDATA[
$( "#feeds" ).load( "feeds.php", {limit: 25}, function() {
  alert( "The last 25 entries in the feed have been loaded" );
});
]]></code>
  </example>
  <category slug="ajax/shorthand-methods"/>
  <category slug="version/1.0"/>
</entry>
