<?xml version="1.0"?>
<argument name="options" type="PlainObject">
	<desc>A map of additional options to pass to the method.</desc>
	<property name="duration" default="400">
		<desc>A string or number determining how long the animation will run.</desc>
		<type name="Number"/>
		<type name="String"/>
	</property>
	<property name="easing" type="String" default="swing">
		<desc>A string indicating which easing function to use for the transition.</desc>
	</property>
	<property name="queue" default="true">
		<desc>A Boolean indicating whether to place the animation in the effects queue. If false, the animation will begin immediately. <strong>As of jQuery 1.7</strong>, the queue option can also accept a string, in which case the animation is added to the queue represented by that string. When a custom queue name is used the animation does not automatically start; you must call <code>.dequeue("queuename")</code> to start it.</desc>
		<type name="Boolean"/>
		<type name="String"/>
	</property>
	<property name="specialEasing" type="PlainObject" added="1.4">
		<desc>A map of one or more of the CSS properties defined by the properties argument and their corresponding easing functions.</desc>
	</property>

	<property name="step" type="Function">
		<desc>A function to be called for each animated property of each animated element. This function provides an opportunity to modify the Tween object to change the value of the property before it is set.</desc>
		<argument name="now" type="Number">
			<desc>The numeric value of the property being animated at each step</desc>
		</argument>
		<argument name="tween" type="Tween">
			<desc>An object of properties related to the animation and the element being animated. For information about the tween object and its properties, see <a href="/jQuery.Tween/">jQuery.Tween</a></desc>
		</argument>
	</property>

	<property name="progress" type="Function" added="1.8">
		<desc>A function to be called after each step of the animation, only once per animated element regardless of the number of animated properties.</desc>
		<argument name="animation" type="Promise">
			<desc>An enhanced Promise object with additional properties for the animation</desc>
		</argument>
		<argument name="progress" type="Number">
			<desc>A number from 0 to 1 indicating the progress of the animation</desc>
		</argument>
		<argument name="remainingMs" type="Number">
			<desc>A number indicating the remaining number of milliseconds until the scheduled end of the animation</desc>
		</argument>
	</property>
	<property name="complete" type="Function">
		<desc>A function to call once the animation is complete.</desc>
		<!-- no parameters -->
	</property>
	<property name="done" type="Function" added="1.8">
		<desc>A function to be called when the animation completes (its Promise object is resolved).</desc>
		<argument name="animation" type="Promise">
			<desc>An enhanced Promise object with additional properties for the animation</desc>
		</argument>
		<argument name="jumpedToEnd" type="Boolean">
			<desc>Indicates whether the animation jumped to the end</desc>
		</argument>
	</property>
	<property name="fail" type="Function" added="1.8">
		<desc>A function to be called when the animation fails to complete (its Promise object is rejected).</desc>
		<argument name="animation" type="Promise">
			<desc>An enhanced Promise object with additional properties for the animation</desc>
		</argument>
		<argument name="jumpedToEnd" type="Boolean">
			<desc>Indicates whether the animation jumped to the end</desc>
		</argument>
	</property>
	<property name="always" type="Function" added="1.8">
		<desc>A function to be called when the animation completes or stops without completing (its Promise object is either resolved or rejected).</desc>
		<argument name="animation" type="Promise">
			<desc>An enhanced Promise object with additional properties for the animation</desc>
		</argument>
		<argument name="jumpedToEnd" type="Boolean">
			<desc>Indicates whether the animation jumped to the end</desc>
		</argument>
	</property>

</argument>
